It ain't ogre...til it's ogre.
Shrek Forever After is a comedy, adventure,
fantasy film directed by Mike Mitchell.
A midlife-crisis burdened Shrek, longing for the days when he felt like a
real ogre, makes a pact with magic deal-maker Rumpelstiltskin.
But when he's duped and sent to a twisted version of Far Far Away—where Rumpelstiltskin is king, ogres are
hunted, and he and Fiona have never met—he sets out to restore his world and reclaim his true love.
Shrek (voice), played by Mike Myers.
Donkey (voice), played by Eddie Murphy.
Princess Fiona (voice), played by Cameron Diaz.
Puss in Boots (voice), played by Antonio Banderas.
Rumpelstiltskin / Priest / Krekraw Ogre (voice), played by Walt Dohrn.
Queen Lillian (voice), played by Julie Andrews.
Shrek Forever After is a 2010 American animated fantasy comedy film
loosely based on the 1990 children's picture book Shrek!
by William Steig.
Directed by Mike Mitchell, and written by Josh Klausner and Darren
Lemke, it is the fourth installment in the Shrek franchise.
The film stars Mike Myers, Eddie Murphy, Cameron Diaz, Antonio Banderas, Julie Andrews, and John Cleese
reprising their voice roles from the previous films, with Walt Dohrn joining the cast.
The story follows Shrek, now a domesticated family man and local celebrity, longing for his days of solitude and being
feared, leading him to make a magic deal with the deceitful imp Rumpelstiltskin, which creates grave consequences.
Shrek Forever After premiered at the Tribeca Film Festival on April 21, 2010, and was
theatrically released by Paramount Pictures in the United States on May 21.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $756
million, becoming the fifth-highest-grossing film of 2010.
Although intended to be the final film in the
series, a fifth film is in development.
Two spin-off films, Puss in Boots (2011) and Puss in Boots: The Last Wish (2022), have also
been released, while a spin-off centered around Donkey is in development.
The film explores themes of witch, villain, sequel, ogre.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.